These 13 teeth prove that this story of
human evolution is totally wrong. Teeth
are made up of the hardest substance in
your body. They're stronger than your
bones, which is why archaeologists find
them a lot. If they inspected your
teeth, they could see micro scratches
and enamel thickness and bumps and know
how old you were and what you ate and
crucially what species you are. Like
this is Lucy, one of the most important
fossils ever. For a long time we thought
that Lucy's species died out and then a
species of ancient human came on the
scene in this march of progress. But
then, when scientists found these 13
teeth, they were able to date them to
nearly 3 million years ago, when we knew
ancient humans lived because of this
other jaw bone that we found. So
everyone else should have been long
gone, but these teeth aren't human.
They're much closer to Lucy's species.
So scientists think that this is a new
unnamed species that coexisted with
ancient human, which means that
evolution from the very start was
basically test driving lots of different
kinds of species often all at once
before ultimately landing on us. But
what else can you tell from a human
skeleton? To see that, subscribe.